tespa.org 2019-07-20

# 

TESPA ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY

Tespa and its affiliate companies (collectively “Tespa”) respect the privacy of its online visitors and recognize the importance of providing a secure environment for them. We have adopted an Online Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store, and use the information you provide us. This Privacy Policy details how Tespa safeguards the privacy of its online visitors and does not apply to information that may be collected by Tespa offline. Please note that when you link to other sites from a Tespa website, this Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities on, those other sites.

What personal information is collected?

Tespa only collects personal information on a voluntary basis. If an online visitor submits information to Tespa, it will usually take the form of either: (1) account registration, or registration for competitions, (2) Recruit-a-Friend e-mails, (3) the purchase of goods through our online store, (4) contest registrations, (5) surveys, (6) customer service or technical support, and/or (7) competition updates and newsletters. Personal information collected may include your name, home address, phone number, and/or e-mail address. We do not require this information to gain access to our sites, however, you will not be able to utilize certain services or features that require registration or receive materials such as competition updates unless such information is provided.

Visitors purchasing products or services will be required to provide additional information such as a valid credit card number, expiration date, and shipping and billing addresses.

Please note that, depending on the Tespa site that you are visiting, many of the activities listed above may not be available and, as such, personal information may not be collected.

What other types of information may we collect?

For some activities, we may ask you to create a username and password and/or to provide other, non-personal information such as your college, age, date of birth, date of graduation, gender, gamer IDs, social media IDs, and/or game and platform preferences; and, combine such information with your personal information. In addition, your web browser or client software may transmit certain geographic information or information regarding your computer (capabilities, unique device ID or other device identifier, browser history, click paths, etc.) to Tespa. Tespa may use this information to generate aggregate statistics about our user community and may provide such information to advertisers and/or our partners. In addition, Tespa may use such information for security, system integrity, or enforcement purposes.

How do we use your personal information?

The personal information you provide Tespa will allow us to manage your account and tournament participation, fulfill your product or service order; alert you of new tournaments, features, or enhancements; handle/route your customer service or technical support questions or issues; to send “Recruit-a-Friend” emails; and/or notify you of contests, promotions, or special events and offers. Tespa may enhance or merge the personal information collected at a Tespa site with data from third parties in order to update your contact information, perform market analysis, or improve our services or systems. Tespa may also provide your personal information to other companies or organizations that are organizing a competition or that offer products or services that may be of interest to you. In such cases, we will notify you that the information will be shared and provide you with an opportunity to opt-out.

Lastly, we may use your personal information for internal marketing, profiling, or demographic purposes, so we can adapt our services to better suit your needs. We do this to better understand and serve our users

Please be advised that personal information submitted by individuals acting solely in a business capacity (e.g., personal information contained in job applicant’s resume) is not subject to the uses set forth above or to any other practices stated in this Privacy Policy.

What type of communications may I receive?

SPECIAL OFFERS AND UPDATES

We will occasionally send you information on competitions, products, services, special deals, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice” section below.

SERVICE-RELATED ANNOUNCEMENTS

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

CUSTOMER SERVICE

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

RECRUIT A FRIEND

If you choose to use our recruit-a-friend features, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to join an upcoming competition or visit the site. Tespa does not store this information and uses it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and to track the success of our referral program.

Who is collecting your information?

When you are asked for information while on a Tespa site, you are sharing that information with Tespa, its parent, and its various affiliates, unless specifically stated otherwise. As a result of this sharing, you may receive communications from any of Tespa’s affiliates. From time to time, Tespa may use third party contractors to collect and process personal information on its behalf (for product and prize fulfillment, credit card processing, etc.).

In addition, some services are provided in conjunction with partner companies (e.g. another competition organizer). If your personal information is being collected by a company other than Tespa and not on Tespa’s behalf, you will be notified at the time the information is collected. If you do not want your information shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of information by not using that particular service or by not providing any information at that time.

Please be aware that we cannot control the activities of third parties to whom we provide data, and as such we cannot guarantee that they adhere to the same privacy and security procedures as Tespa.

Please be aware that advertisers or websites with links to and from our sites may collect personal information about you. And remember, this Privacy Policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities of, those other advertisers or websites.

Our websites may include certain social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

With whom may your personal information be shared?

Tespa will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may, however, share non-personally identifiable, aggregated, and/or public information with third parties.

We may need to disclose your personal information to third party vendors to fulfill product orders or prizes, to process mailings, or to process, analyze, and/or store data on Tespa’s behalf. We will attempt to ensure that these entities do not use your personal information for any other purpose, and that they have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the personal information they obtain from us. These service providers may not use your personal information for their own marketing purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against you if you may be causing injury to or interference (intentionally or unintentionally) with Tespa’s rights or property, other users of a Tespa site or service, or anyone else who could be harmed by your activities. We also reserve the right to disclose your personal information if we have a good faith belief that it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activities.

As with any business, your personal information is also an asset of Tespa and will become part of our normal business records. As such, we may also disclose your personal information to a third party if we decide to sell a line of business to that third party, so you can continue to receive service and information in connection with that line of business with as little disruption as possible. Similarly, in the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy, or other similar event, your personal information may be transferred to Tespa ‘s successor or assign.

Tespa sites may also have message boards, forums, and/or chat areas, where users can exchange ideas and communicate with one another. When posting to a message board, forum, or chat area, please be aware that the information is being made publicly available on-line and the user does so at his or her own risk. If your personal information is posted on one of our community forums, you may contact us at privacy@tespa.org. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

What choices do I have regarding the collection, use, and distribution of my personal information?

Tespa allows you to control the way that we use personal identifying information that we might obtain. At the time you provide personal information, Tespa may give you the option of declining any future offers or information about new products, promotions, or services. In addition, many of the “mailings” Tespa may send you, such as newsletters, have procedures within them to cancel the receipt of any future mailings. Lastly, you may be given the opportunity to “opt-out” of certain features or functionality.

California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights

Under California law, our customers that are California residents may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. As detailed above, we do not share our customer’s personal information with unaffiliated third parties for direct marketing purposes without their approval.

If at any time you wish to opt out of having your personal information shared with third parties and/or receiving information from Tespa (via e-mail or postal mail) about new products, services, or promotions, you can do so. You may contact us at Tespa Privacy Policy, Attn: Opt-Out Administrator, 16215 Alton Pkwy. Irvine CA 92618-3616. You can also contact us by e-mailing us at opt-out@tespa.org. Please indicate what publications or services you no longer wish to receive so that we may better address your needs.

What about Children?

CHILDREN UNDER 13

Once a child states that his/her age is under 13, we do not collect or store any personally identifiable information such as name, address, or email address.

What are tracking technologies and how are they used?

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

Technologies such as: cookies, clear gifs, tags and scripts are used by Tespa and our partners such as marketing partners and analytics providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well aggregated basis.

We use cookies for various purposes including to remember users’ settings and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

We may also use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. For this reason, these types of clear gifs are tied to personally identifiable information.

We may use Local Storage Objects (“LSOs”) such as HTML5 of Flash to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please[ click here.](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

What are Internet protocol addresses?

An Internet protocol (“IP”) address is the unique number assigned to your server or Internet Service Provider (“ISP”). Tespa may track such IP addresses for system administration, to report aggregate information, site tracking, security purposes, or to prevent our servers from being abused.

What do I do if I want to correct or delete my personal information?

If for any reason you are concerned with the way we are using your personal information, or would like to correct or request that we delete such personal information, please contact Tespa Privacy Policy, Attention: Privacy Policy Administrator, at 16215 Alton Pkwy. Irvine CA 92618-3616. You can also contact us by e-mailing us at privacy@tespa.org. We will respond to any request for access within 30 days.

In some cases, we may not be able to delete your personal information and will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Please note that the deletion of your data will lead to the termination of your account and applicable services.

How secure is my personal information?

Tespa has taken steps to assure that all information collected will remain secure and in its original form, i.e. free from any alteration. As such, access to all personal information is strictly controlled. When credit card information is transmitted, for example, we use industry standard, SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption. In addition, we will take reasonable steps to assure that third parties to whom we transfer any data will provide sufficient protection of personal information. We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you services.

What if I have a question or complaint?

If you have any questions or wish to file a complaint, please feel free to e-mail us at[ privacy@tespa.org ](mailto:privacy@tespa.org)or send a letter addressed to Tespa Privacy Policy, Attention: Privacy Policy Administrator, at 16215 Alton Pkwy. Irvine CA 92618-3616.

By using this website and/or any of Tespa’s online services, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use this site. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes. If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting the change on this website or in this Privacy Policy and, if necessary, give you additional choices regarding such change prior to the change becoming effective. Your continued use of the Tespa website will signify your acceptance of these changes.

This Privacy Policy was posted on March 6, 2015
